Let's talk trash.
لنتحدث عن القمامة
You know, we had to be taught
أتعلمون ، كان علينا أن نتعلم
to renounce the powerful conservation ethic
أن ننبذ الأخلاقيات المحافظة المسيطرة
we developed during the Great Depression and World War II.
التي اكتسبناها خلال الكساد العظيم والحرب العالمية الثانية
After the war, we needed to direct our enormous production capacity
بعد الحرب ، احتجنا إلى توجيه طاقتنا الإنتاجية الهائلة
toward creation of products for peacetime.
لصناعة منتجات لزمن السلم
Life Magazine helped in this effort
مجلة لايف ساعدت في هذا المجهود
by announcing the introduction of throwaways
بإعلان وصول المرميات
that would liberate the housewife from the drudgery of doing dishes.
التي ستحرر الزوجة من شقاء غسيل الصحون
Mental note to the liberators:
ملاحظة فكرية للمحررين:
throwaway plastics take a lot of space and don't biodegrade.
المرميات البلاستيكية تأخذ مساحات كبيرة ولا تتحلل
Only we humans make waste that nature can't digest.
فقط نحن البشر ننتج فضلات لا تستطيع الطبيعة هضمها
Plastics are also hard to recycle.
إن إعادة تصنيع البلاستيك صعبة أيضاً
A teacher told me how to express the under-five-percent
أخبرني مدرس كيف أعبر عن الأقل من 5%
of plastics recovered in our waste stream.
من البلاستيك الذي يسترجع من فضلاتنا
It's diddly-point-squat.
وهو صفر فاصلة لاشيء
That's the percentage we recycle.
تلك هي النسبة التي نعيد تصنيعها
Now, melting point has a lot to do with this.
ولنقطة الانصهار أثر كبير في ذلك
Plastic is not purified by the re-melting process like glass and metal.
البلاستيك لا ينقى بعملية إعادة الصهر كما هو الحال في الزجاج والمعادن
It begins to melt below the boiling point of water
فهو يبدأ بالانصهار تحت نقطة غليان الماء
and does not drive off the oily contaminants
ولا يتخلص من الملوثات الزيتية
for which it is a sponge.
الذي يمتصها كالإسفنج
Half of each year's 100 billion pounds of thermal plastic pellets
نصف الـ 100 بليون كرية بلاستيكية حرارية من كل سنة
will be made into fast-track trash.
ستتحول إلى قمامة المسار السريع
A large, unruly fraction of our trash
وجزء كبير جداً من قمامتنا
will flow downriver to the sea.
سينساب مع الأنهار إلى البحر
Here is the accumulation at Biona Creek next to the L.A. airport.
هذا هو التجمع قرب المطار في خور بيونا
And here is the flotsam near California State University Long Beach
وهذا هو التجمع الطافي قرب جامعة ولاية كاليفورنيا بلونج بيتش
and the diesel plant we visited yesterday.
ومحطة التحلية التي زرناها البارحة
In spite of deposit fees,
بالرغم من الرسوم المفروضة
much of this trash leading out to the sea will be plastic beverage bottles.
فإن معظم تلك القمامة المتجهة نحو البحر هي القوارير البلاستيكية للمشروبات
We use two million of them in the United States every five minutes,
نحن نستهلك ٢ مليون منها في الولايات المتحدة كل خمس دقائق
here imaged by TED presenter Chris Jordan,
هنا وقد صورها مقدم تيد كريس جوردان
who artfully documents mass consumption and zooms in for more detail.
والذي يوثق الاستهلاك الضخم بشكل فني ويقرب الصورة للمزيد من التفاصيل
Here is a remote island repository for bottles
هذا مخزون قوارير في جزيرة نائية
off the coast of Baja California.
قرب ساحل باها كاليفورنيا
Isla San Roque is an uninhabited bird rookery
إسلا سان روقي هي جزيرة غير مأهولة لأسراب الطيور
off Baja's sparsely populated central coast.
قرب ساحل باها المركزي القليل السكان
Notice that the bottles here have caps on them.
لاحظوا أن القوارير هنا لها أغطية
Bottles made of polyethylene terephthalate, PET,
القوارير المصنوعة من تيريفثاليت البولي إثيلين
will sink in seawater and not make it this far from civilization.
ستغرق في ماء البحر ولن تستطيع الوصول لهذا البعد عن الحضارة
Also, the caps are produced in separate factories
كما آن الأغطية تنتج في مصانع مختلفة
from a different plastic, polypropylene.
من نوع آخر من البلاستيك، البولي بروبيلين
They will float in seawater,
ستطفو في مياه البحار
but unfortunately do not get recycled under the bottle bills.
وللأسف لا يتم تكريرها وفقاً قانون القوارير
Let's trace the journey of the millions of caps
لنتبع رحلة ملايين الأغطية
that make it to sea solo.
التي تصل إلى البحار
After a year the ones from Japan are heading straight across the Pacific,
بعد عام تعبر تلك القادمة من اليابان المحيط الهادئ
while ours get caught in the California current
بينما خاصتنا تعلق في تيار كاليفورنيا
and first head down to the latitude of Cabo San Lucas.
وتتجه أولًا إلى مستوى كابو سان لوكاس
After ten years, a lot of the Japanese caps
بعد عشر أعوام، الكثير من أغطية اليابان
are in what we call the Eastern Garbage Patch,
هي في ما نسميه رقعة القمامة الشرقية
while ours litter the Philippines.
بينما تلوث أغطيتنا الفلبين
After 20 years, we see emerging the debris accumulation zone
بعد 20 عام، نرى منطقة تجمع الركام الناشئة
of the North Pacific Gyre.
في شمال المحيط الهادئ
It so happens that millions of albatross
ويصادف أن الملايين من طيور القطرس
nesting on Kure and Midway atolls
تعشعش على كوري وجزر ميدويه المرجانية
in the Northwest Hawaiian Islands National Monument
في النصب الوطني لجزر هاواي الشمال غربية
forage here and scavenge whatever they can find
تأكل هنا وتلتقط كل ما يمكنها إيجاده
for regurgitation to their chicks.
لتجترها وتطعمها لصغارها
A four-month old Laysan Albatross chick
صغير قطرس عمره أربعة أشهر
died with this in its stomach.
مات وهذا في بطنه
Hundreds of thousands of the goose-sized chicks are dying
مئات الآلاف من صغار الوز يموتون
with stomachs full of bottle caps and other rubbish,
ببطون مليئة بالأغطية وقاذورات أخرى
like cigarette lighters ...
كولاعات السجائر
but, mostly bottle caps.
ولكن ، في الغالب أغطية قوارير
Sadly, their parents mistake bottle caps for food
للأسف ، يظن آبائهم خطأً أن الأغطية هي طعام
tossing about in the ocean surface.
تتقاذفه الأمواج على سطح المحيط
The retainer rings for the caps
حلقات تثبيت الأغطية
also have consequences for aquatic animals.
لها أثر على الحيوانات البحرية
This is Mae West,
هذه ماي ويست
still alive at a zookeeper's home in New Orleans.
لا تزال حية في منزل حارس في حديقة الحيوان في نيو أوريلانز
I wanted to see what my home town of Long Beach was contributing to the problem,
أردت أن أرى مساهمة مدينتي لونج بيتش في المشكلة
so on Coastal Clean-Up Day in 2005
لذا في يوم تنظيف الشاطئ 2005
I went to the Long Beach Peninsula, at the east end of our long beach.
ذهبت إلى شبه جزيرة لونج بيتش في الطرف الشرقي من شاطئنا الطويل
We cleaned up the swaths of beach shown.
نقوم بتنظيف المساحات الظاهرة من الشاطئ
I offered five cents each for bottle caps.
عرضت خمس سنتات لكل غطاء قارورة
I got plenty of takers.
حصلت على الكثير من المطالبين
Here are the 1,100 bottle caps they collected.
هذه 1,100 غطاء قاموا بجمعها
I thought I would spend 20 bucks.
اعتقدت أنني سأصرف 20 دولار
That day I ended up spending nearly 60.
إنتها بي اليوم وقد صرفت 60
I separated them by color
صنفتهم حسب اللون
and put them on display the next Earth Day
وعرضتهم في يوم الأرض التالي
at Cabrillo Marine Aquarium in San Pedro.
في حديقة كابيريللو البحرية في سان بيدرو
Governor Schwarzenegger and his wife Maria stopped by to discuss the display.
الحاكم شوارزنجر وزوجته ماريا مرا بي لمناقشة العرض
In spite of my "girly man" hat, crocheted from plastic shopping bags,
بالرغم من قبعتي النسائية الرجالية ، المصنوعة من أكياس بلاستيكية ،
they shook my hand. (Laughter)
صافحاني باليد
I showed him and Maria a zooplankton trawl
أريته وماريا شبكة جر لصيد العوالق الحيوانية
from the gyre north of Hawaii
من تيارات شمال هاواي
with more plastic than plankton.
فيها بلاستيك أكثر من العوالق
Here's what our trawl samples from the plastic soup our ocean has become look like.
ها هي عيناتنا لشبكات الجر من شوربة البلاستيك التي الذي أصبح عليها المحيط
Trawling a zooplankton net on the surface for a mile
من جر شبكة للعوالق على السطح لمسافة ميل
produces samples like this.
نحصل على عينات كهذه
And this.
وهذه
Now, when the debris washes up on the beaches of Hawaii
الآن، عندما يقذف المحيط بالركام على شواطئ هاواي
it looks like this.
يبدو هكذا
And this particular beach is Kailua Beach,
وهذا الشاطئ تحديداً هو شاطئ كايلوا
the beach where our president and his family vacationed before moving to Washington.
حيث قضى رئيسنا وعائلته عطلتهم قبل الانتقال إلى واشنطن
Now, how do we analyze samples like this one
الآن، كيف نحلل عينات كهذه
that contain more plastic than plankton?
التي تحوي بلاستيك أكثر من العوالق
We sort the plastic fragments into different size classes,
نفرز قطع البلاستيك إلى فئات حجمية مختلفة
from five millimeters to one-third of a millimeter.
من ثلث ملم إلى خمس ملم
Small bits of plastic concentrate persistent organic pollutants
قطع صغيرة من مركز الملوثات العضوية الثابتة البلاستيكية
up to a million times their levels in the surrounding seawater.
تصل إلى مليون مرة من مستواها في مياه البحر المحيطة بها
We wanted to see if the most common fish in the deep ocean,
أردنا أن نعرف إذا كان أكثر الأسماك شيوعًا في المحيط العميق
at the base of the food chain,
في قاعدة السلسلة الغذائية
was ingesting these poison pills.
يبتلع هذه الحبوب السامة
We did hundreds of necropsies,
قمنا بمئات التشاريح
and over a third had polluted plastic fragments in their stomachs.
أكثر من الثلث كان بداخل بطونهم بلاستيك ملوث
The record-holder, only two-and-a-half inches long,
ساحب الرقم القياسي، فقط بطول بوصتين ونصف
had 84 pieces in its tiny stomach.
كان لديا 84 قطعة في معدتها الصغيرة
Now, you can buy certified organic produce.
الآن، يمكنك أن تشتري منتجات عضوية مصدقة
But no fishmonger on Earth
لكن لا يستطيع أي صياد على وجه الأرض
can sell you a certified organic wild-caught fish.
أن يبيعك سمك عضوي مصدق تم صيده برياً
This is the legacy we are leaving to future generations.
هذا هو الإرث الذي نتركه لأجيالنا القادمة
The throwaway society cannot be contained --
مجتمع المرميات لا يمكن احتوائه
it has gone global.
لقد أصبح عالمياً
We simply cannot store and maintain or recycle all our stuff.
نحن ببساطة لا نسطيع تخزين، صيانة أو إعادة تصنيع كل أغراضنا
We have to throw it away.
لابد أن نرميها
Now, the market can do a lot for us,
يمكن للسوق فعل المزيد من أجلنا
but it can't fix the natural system in the ocean we've broken.
لكنه لا يستطيع إصلاح النظام الطبيعي للمحيط الذي قمنا بكسره
All the king's horses and all the king's men ...
جميع فرسان الملك وكل رجاله
will never gather up all the plastic and put the ocean back together again.
لن يتمكنوا من جمع كل البلاستيك وإعادة المحيط كما كان سابقاً
Narrator (Video): The levels are increasing,
فيديو: المستويات في ارتفاع
the amount of packaging is increasing,
حجم التعليب والتغليف في ازدياد
the "throwaway" concept of living is proliferating,
وطريقة حياة المرميات في ازدياد
and it's showing up in the ocean.
وتظهر في المحيط
Anchor: He offers no hope of cleaning it up.
المعلق: إنه لا يرى أي أمل في تنظيفها
Straining the ocean for plastic
تصفية المحيط من البلاستيك
would be beyond the budget of any country
أكبر من ميزانية أي دولة
and it might kill untold amounts of sea life in the process.
وقد تقتل أعدادا لاتحصى من الأحياء البحرية خلال العملية
The solution, Moore says, is to stop the plastic at its source:
الحل، يقول مورو ، هو إيقاف البلاستيك من المصدر
stop it on land before it falls in the ocean.
إيقافه على اليابسة قبل سقوطه في المحيط
And in a plastic-wrapped and packaged world,
وفي عالمم معلب ملفوف بالأكياس البلاستيكية.
he doesn't hold out much hope for that, either.
وهو لا يأمل بالكثير بهذا الخصوص
This is Brian Rooney for Nightline,
هنا براين رووني من نايت لاين
in Long Beach, California.
في لونج بيتش، كاليفورنيا
Charles Moore: Thank you.
شارلز موور: شكراً